Previously on "Once Upon a Time"...
童話歸來 前情提要
Rumplestiltskin, scared of ending up just like his coward father
侏儒怪 害怕落得跟他的懦弱老爸一般下場
Papa.No
爸爸 不要
A young boy will lead you to your son
一個小男孩會帶你找到你的兒子
What's going on
出了什麼事
The boy will be your undoing
這個男孩將是你毀滅的原因
Once you drink this water,you can never leave Neverland
你一喝下這水 就再也無法離開永恆島了
It's a small price to pay for what I get in return
相對於我得到的回報來說 這代價太小了
- What do you need him to believe in -  me
- 你要讓他信奉什麼? - 我自己
Inside is where our salvation awaits
我們的救贖正在裡面等待著
Are you up to the task
你能勝任這個任務嗎?
Follow the lady,gents
看好卡片中的女士 先生們
A shilling returns two
買一賠二
What
什麼?
Don't feel too bad
別難過
You're not the only one who's been spurned by the lady tonight
今晚不止你一個人被這位女士拒之門外
She's been quite shy all evening
她整晚都挺害羞的
You tricked me
你耍我
How'd she get in there
她怎麼跑到那裡去了
Please,don't hurt him.He's my father
求求你別傷害他 他是我父親
You'd be better off without him
沒有他你會過得更好
No,no
不要 不要
Are you okay
你還好嗎?
The cost of the game
遊戲的代價
He didn't even leave me a shilling for a pint.How rude
他連一個子兒的酒錢都沒給我留下 真野蠻
He took all of our money
他把我們所有錢都搶走了?
Yes,but I'll figure something out
是 但我會想到辦法的
I always do... Rumple
我總有辦法的... Rumple
Roll up
快來
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-Proudly Presents
-=伊甸園美劇 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=伊甸園字幕站 http://ytet.org=- 榮譽出品 本字幕僅供學習交流 嚴禁用於商業用途
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com/bbs=-Sync: YTET-可可与可心
-=YTEY-伊甸園字幕組-歆組=- 翻譯: 梨渦淺笑 霄霄 怡豆 校對: 尉遲逸 時間軸: 可可與可心
Once Upon a Time 3 Episode 8
童話歸來 第三季 第8集
How is she
她怎麼樣了?
I fear she's getting worse,Henry
恐怕情況不妙 Henry
- But if I save magic... She'll live? - Yes
- 如果我拯救了魔法... 她就能活下去? - 是的
But more than that,Henry
不只是她 Henry
If you save magic,you'll save us all
如果你拯救了魔法 就是救了我們所有人
But to do it,you have to truly believe
但首先你的信念要十分堅定才行
I do
我做得到
Good,because we don't have much time
很好 我們時間不多了
Follow me
跟我來
My brothers
兄弟們
Tonight,the dream of Neverland will awaken from its slumber
今晚 永恆島的夢想將從沉睡中甦醒
Tonight,the heart of the truest believer shall fulfill its destiny,
今晚 最虔誠信徒的心將履行它的使命
and with it our destiny
還有我們的使命
Tonight,Henry saves magic
今晚 Henry要拯救魔法
You know,despite our differences,
知道嗎 雖然我們之間有差異
I can always count on you to get things done... Unlike the rest of them
但我總能指望你做些事情... 不像其他人
You were right
你說的對
They're just a liability
他們只會誤事
Where are they
他們去哪了?
Oh,well,Pan told them Neal was alive, and,of course,Emma took the bait
彼得潘告訴他們Neal還活著 Emma當然上鉤了
Such a waste of time
簡直是浪費時間
Oh,I'm so sorry
對不住
- No,no,don't be. - He is alive. - What?
- 不用 他是還活著 - 什麼?
Pan wasn't lying
彼得潘沒說謊
My son is here on the island.I've seen him
我兒子就在這島上 我見過他
You saw him and you... you just parted ways
你見過他 然後... 又分開了?
You realize that he might have a way off the island
你知道他說不定有辦法離開這個島
Let's worry about the travel plans after we get Henry
我們還是在救出Henry後 再關心行動路線吧
There's something you're not telling me
你有事瞞著我
What happened when you saw him
你見到他以後發生了什麼事?
Look,all you have to know is,the next time I see him will be
你只需知道 我下次見他的時候
when I'm putting Henry in his arms
就是把Henry交到他手裡的時候
When father and son are reunited
讓他們父子團聚
Where are we
我們在哪?
These nice ladies are going to look after you for a little while
這些善良的女士會照顧你一段時間
- You must be the boy... - Rumplestiltskin
- 你就是那個男孩... - Rumplestiltskin
- Do you know how to spin? - We can teach you
- 你會紡紗嗎? - 我們教你
I... I don't want to stay here
我... 不想待在這兒
Please,I... I'll be good
求你了 我... 我會聽話
This will give me time to get a real job, so we can be together
這樣我才有時間找份像樣的工作 然後我們就又能在一起了
We can be together right now
我們現在就能在一起
Papa,please.Don't leave me here
爸爸 求求你 別把我扔在這兒
Don't be scared now
別害怕
Hey,I got you a present.A friend
嘿 我給你帶了一個禮物 一位朋友
Someone to be at your side when I'm away
我不在的時候 有它陪著你
It will be with you when I cannot
我不在你身邊的時候 它就會在
- It will? - Give it a name
- 它會嗎? - 給它取個名吧
Names always make things better
名字總會讓事情好轉
They make them real.Trust me
名字會讓它們變真實 相信我
It will protect you
它會保護你
And I'll be back before you know it
我很快就會回來
I promise
我保證
I'm gonna ask Tink how close we are to Pan's compound
我去問問叮噹 我們離彼得潘的地盤還有多遠
I don't wanna be surprised by any lost boys on patrol
我可不想被巡邏的迷失男孩發現
Good idea
好主意
Looks like you two buried the hatchet
看來你倆和好如初了
Buried.I don't know
和好 我也不知道
We've at least put it away for now
我們只是暫時放下矛盾不提而已
So you're really gonna stay here with him
那你真的打算留在這裡陪他?
The thought of leaving you,Emma,it kills me
一想到要離開你 Emma 我心都痛死了
But there's nothing we can do
但我們沒有別的辦法
If David leaves the island,he'll die
如果David離開這個島 他就會死
So you're just giving up
所以你們只有放棄
Family means being together,all of us
家庭意味著我們全家人在一起生活
But there's no other way
但真沒別的辦法呀
Maybe this is just you rubbing off on me, but I don't believe that
也許這就是你遺傳給我的性格 我只是一直不相信而已
There's always a way
一定會有辦法的
Well,if this is your version of a rescue party, we got here just in time
如果這就是你們所謂的營救陣容 那我們來的正是時候
What are you two doing here
你倆在這兒做什麼?
Well,same as you, except we actually have a chance
跟你們一樣 不同的是 我們有成功的機會
Pandora's box
潘多拉的盒子
It could trap Pan for eternity simply by opening the lid
只要打開蓋子 就能抓住彼得潘 永世也不得翻身
- You didn't tell me my father was with her. - I didn't know
- 你沒告訴我我爸跟她在一起 - 我也不知道
Wait,your father is the Dark One
等等 你爸是黑暗使者?
Yeah,and he's not getting anywhere near Henry
是的 而且他不能接近Henry
- Bae... - Why?What are you talking about
- Bae... - 為什麼? 你這話是什麼意思?
There's a prophecy that says that Henry will be his undoing
有個預言說Henry會是他毀滅的原因
He didn't come here to protect him
他來這裡不是保護他
He came here to kill him
而是要殺他
That's why you didn't want to find Neal before you got Henry back
所以你才不想在救出Henry之前 跟Neal會合
Because you knew he'd spill your secret
因為你知道他會洩露你的秘密
Everything I did was to protect Henry, to rescue him from Pan
我做所有事都是為了保護Henry 把他從彼得潘手上救出來
It all makes sense
一切都說得通了
You left before we even made shore
我們靠岸前你就先走了
- You wanted to get to Henry first. - To be on his own
- 你想先找到Henry - 自己一個人找到
So no one could stop you... So you can kill him
- 那樣就沒人能阻止你... - 你就能殺了他
It's not gonna happen, not unless you go through all of us first
這事絕不可能發生 除非你先幹掉我們
Someone so young... In such a short time.Look at him
年輕真好 這麼短的時間 看看他
He could spin for... for kings and queens one day
總有一天 他都能給國王和王后紡線了
- I didn't think I had any talent. - Oof,more than talent.A gift
- 我不覺得自己有什麼才華 - 才不只是才華 而是天賦
You could apprentice with anyone in the land
你能出去給人做學徒了
If I can make money, then my father and I can be together
如果我能賺錢 就能跟爸爸在一起了
Rumple... even with your talent, too many people know your father is a cheat
Rumple... 就算你再有才華 人們也都當你爸爸是騙子
And a coward
還是個膽小鬼
If you are to have a happy life, you must go somewhere
如果你想過快樂的日子 必須離開
where your father's name cannot follow you
去一個沒受你爸爸污名影響的地方
You mean... alone
你的意思是... 我自己去?
This bean... can open a portal, take you far away from this land
這顆豆子... 能打開傳送門 令你遠離這個是非之地
Even this realm
甚至這個王國
You could start a new life
你可以開始新的生活
But it cannot be with your father
但不能和你爸爸在一起
But he's coming back for me as soon as he gets a job
但是他一找到工作就會回來找我
- The truth is,he's at the pub.He doesn't want a job. - Or real responsibility
- 事實是他成天泡在酒吧 並不想找工作 - 也不想承擔責任
Family can be a strength,but it can also be a burden
家人能給人力量 但也會成為負擔
And your father will always be your burden,Rumplestiltskin
你爸爸永遠是你的負擔 Rumplestiltskin
You're making a mistake
你們都錯了
I don't care if the boy is destined to be my undoing
我不在乎那男孩是否注定 會造成我的毀滅
I won't hurt him
我不會傷害他
Because that sounds just like you
可這聽起來就是你的處事風格
Without me,you will fail
沒有我 你們就會失敗
I'm the most powerful amongst us
我是我們這些人中法力最強的
That's why we can't trust you
所以我們才無法相信你
If I could give you my dagger,I would But I can't
如果可以 我會把我的匕首給你們 但我不能
But you can give me Pandora's box
你可以把潘多拉的盒子給我
I don't have to trust you if I could stop you
如果我有阻止你的本事 就不需要相信你了
Son... Look at me, you so much as lift a finger to perform magic,
- 兒子... - 看著我 你要是敢耍什麼花招
you're gonna spend an eternity in this box
就準備永遠待在這盒子裡吧
Let's go
我們走
Look... you may think you know who you're up against, but you don't
聽著... 你以為自己瞭解對手 但你並不瞭解
Then tell me
那就告訴我
What really happened between you two
你倆之間到底發生了什麼事
Peter Pan destroyed my father
彼得潘毀掉了我父親
They were right.You're here
她們說的對 你果然在這
Hey,laddie
嘿 小伙子
My dogs were barking after hitting the cobblestones all morning looking for work
我的狗撞到鵝卵石上就不停地叫 整個早上 我正在找工作
Then these fellas told me that they never played "find the lady"
接著這些夥計對我說他們從來 都沒玩過"找女士"的遊戲
Rumple Come on Rumple
Rumple 回來 Rumple
You said you were finding a job
你說你在找工作
No one in this town would hire me
這鎮上沒人會雇我的
Because no one trusts you
因為沒人相信你
But you do
但你相信我
Don't you,son
是不是 兒子?
I want to
我想相信你
What if there was someplace we could start over
我們能不能去別的地方重新開始?
Somewhere where no one knew you
去一個沒人認識你的地方
How
怎麼去?
With this
用這個
Where'd you get that
你從哪得到這東西?
Do you know how much money a bean like that would fetch
你知不知道一顆這樣的豆子 能賣多少錢?
No,it's mine.I won't let you gamble it away
它不是我的 我不能讓你拿它去賭
Rumple,you don't understand
Rumple 你不懂
I understand this bean can take us someplace... where no one knows us
我知道這顆豆子能帶我們去某個地方 沒人認識我們的地方
Where we can be a family
在那裡我們還是一家人
- A real fresh start - Yes
- 一個全新的開始 - 是的
I trust you
我相信你
Then where should we go
那我們去哪呢?
There must be someplace special to you
你一定有特別喜歡的地方
Think,think
快想 快想
Think,think,think,think,think
快想 快想 快想
Think lovely thoughts
想些愉快的事
- That's it. - What
- 有了 - 什麼
When I was a boy, my father sold me to a blacksmith
小時候 我父親把我賣給一個鐵匠
All day in front of hot coals,the sweat and the grime
整天面對著熱炭 汗水 煤灰
But every night I would say to myself, "think lovely thoughts"
每天晚上我都對自己說 "想些愉快的事"
And in my sleep,I would travel to the most wonderful place
於是在睡夢中 我來到非常美妙的地方
- What was it called? - Neverland
- 那個地方叫什麼? - 永恆島
Then that's where we should go
那麼我們就去那兒吧
I don't even know if this place is real
我都不知道這個地方是不是真的存在
We need to talk
我們得談談
I've found when a woman says that, I'm rarely in for pleasant conversation
我發現每當女人說這話的時候 談話內容多半不怎麼開心
There has to be a way for David to leave the island
一定有個辦法能讓David離開這島
Well,there isn't
根本沒有
He told me about your brother,what happened
他給我講了你哥哥的事 後來怎樣了?
I know it can't be easy to talk about,but... Well,then let's not,shall we
- 我知道這話題並不輕鬆.. - 那就別問了 好嗎?
The water that cured David from dreamshade has connected him to the island
把David的夢影毒治好的泉水 將他和這島連在一起
If he leaves,the connection is broken
如果他離開 連接就會中斷
The poison will kill him
他就會中毒而死
What if we take some of the water with us
那要是我們帶走一些水呢?
That way he stays connected
這樣連接會一直保持著
He can stay alive in Storybrooke
他能在童話鎮生活下去
For how long
活多久?
Once the water runs out, the dreamshade will take his life
水一旦用光 夢影毒就會要了他的命
Unless there was another cure
除非有別的治療方法
You suddenly interested in what I have to say
你們突然對我說的話感興趣了
Thought I wasn't to be trusted
我還以為自己不被人信任呢
You're not,but I'll take my chances
你是不被人信任 我只是碰碰運氣
Well,if you remember, I,too,was poisoned with dreamshade by a cowardly pirate
如果你還記得 有個怯懦的海盜 也給我下過夢影毒
And yet... Yes,and we know how you cured yourself...
- 而現在... - 是的 我們都知道你怎樣給自己解了毒
with a candle that takes another person's life
用犧牲別人性命的蠟燭
David is not that selfish
David沒那麼自私
Oh,how noble
多麼高尚
The point is,after my near-death experience, I discovered much about the poison
重點是在我瀕死的經歷之後 我對這毒藥有了更深的瞭解
I believe I could create an elixir back in my shop
我相信回我店裡 我能製造出萬能藥
what is your price?
代價是什麼?
Well,this is quite the favor
這我可賣了你很大的人情
- I'd expect one of equal weight in return. - No
- 我會期望有同等價值的作為回報 - 不行
When we get back to Storybrooke, you're gonna save David
等我們回到童話鎮 你要救David
because it's the right thing to do
因為這麼做是正確的
No deals,no favors,understand
不做交易 不欠人情 明白不?
Fine
行
I'll do as you ask
我會照你說的做
I'll go tell David
我去告訴David
We're here
我們到了
Pan's perimeter
彼得潘的地盤
It's time
是時候了
Tink will sneak us in the back like we planned
叮噹仙女會像我們計劃的那樣 從後門偷帶我們進去
We grab Henry.In and out,simple
我們帶上Henry 進去 出來 很簡單
You good with Pan patrol
你能應付得了彼得潘的巡邏隊不?
Locked and loaded
荷槍實彈
You mind if I, borrow this
你介意我借用一下這個嗎?
You said no magic,I agreed
你說過不許用魔法 我同意了
But I'm not walking in there with nothing but my good looks
可我不會啥都不帶就進去 除了我這張漂亮臉蛋
Now I,on the other hand... Here,in case your good looks fail you
- 而我 另一方面講... - 給 以防萬一你那漂亮臉蛋讓你失望了
Thanks,mate
謝了 夥計
Let's get Henry
我們去帶Henry回來吧
Can I at least use magic on these boys
我至少能對這些男孩們用魔法吧?
- No. - I'll do it
- 不行 - 讓我來
You remember the spell
你還記得咒語?
- Where's Pan? - I don't know
- 彼得潘在哪裡? - 我不知道
- Henry - He's gotta be somewhere - Where
- Henry  - 他肯定在某處 - 在哪兒?
Help
救命
You're an... an adult
你是個... 成人
My name's Emma.I'm looking for my son
我叫Emma 我在找我兒子
- Wendy - Do I know you.It's Baelfire
- Wendy  - 我認識你嗎? - 是我 Baelfire
- You two know each other - Bae. - Yeah Yeah,we do
- 你們倆認識? - Bae  - 嗯 我們認識
Can it really be you
真的是你嗎?
I thought I'd never see you again
我以為我再也見不到你了
What are you... wh... what are you doing here
你來這兒... 你來這兒幹什麼?
Well,I... I came back to save you
我回來救你了
You did that for me
你為了我回來了?
Well,I couldn't bear for you to be without a family,
我不能忍受讓你沒有家人的懷抱
not after you told us that your mother and father were both dead
在你告訴我們你父母雙亡之後
You told her I was dead
你告訴她我死了?
It was easier than telling the truth... my own father abandoned me
這比說出真相更容易些... 我的親生父親拋棄了我
We actually did it.We made it
我們真的做到了 我們做到了
It's just as I remember in my dreams
這跟我記得的夢中場景一模一樣
Hasn't changed at all
一點都沒變
It's beautiful
真是美啊
No,it's more than that
不 這可不止是美
Neverland is special
永恆島是很特別的
You can do anything here
你在這兒什麼都能做
Just think it,and it can happen
只要你想像 就能成真
What would you like to eat
你想吃什麼?
Go on.Just think it
來吧 就想像一下
You can eat cake all day and not get a stomachache
你可以吃一整天蛋糕也不會肚子疼
Or swing on a vine through a waterfall
或者蕩著籐條穿過瀑布
But best of all... you can fly
但最棒的是... 你能飛翔
Flying is impossible
飛翔是不可能的
Neverland is where the impossible is possible, if you believe it
永恆島就是把不可能變成可能的地方 只要你相信它
Here,I'll show you
看著 我展示給你看
I don't understand
我不明白
I could always fly when I visited as a boy
我小時候來這兒 隨時都能飛翔
Maybe you can't fly because you're not a boy anymore
或許你不能飛了 是因為你不再是個小男孩了
How could I have forgotten
我怎麼會忘記呢
Of course
當然了
Pixie dust
精靈塵
Even as a boy,you needed pixie dust if you wanted to fly
即使是個男孩 當你想飛時 你也需要精靈塵
- Where do we get some? - Oh,I'll show you
- 我們去哪兒弄些來呢? - 我帶你去
Hey,Wendy, since you've been here,have you seen my son
嘿 Wendy 你來這兒以後 見過我兒子嗎?
His name's Henry
他叫Henry
- You have a son - Yeah
- 你有兒子 - 嗯
Pan needs his heart
彼得潘要他的心
Has he said anything about the heart of the truest believer
他有說過任何關於 "真正信徒的心"的話嗎?
No I'm sorry
沒有 我很抱歉
He never mentioned anything about a heart
他從未提到過什麼"心"
She's lying
她在撒謊
Where is he
他在哪兒?
What the hell are you doing
你在幹什麼?
I've carried enough lies in my life to recognize their burden
我的生命中已有足夠多的謊言 讓我看清它們的負擔
She knows where Henry is
她知道Henry在哪裡
Is that true
他說的是真的嗎?
You don't understand
你不明白
You're helping Pan
你在幫彼得潘
He's keeping John and Michael alive, only if I do as he says
他讓John和Michael活命 條件是我照他說的做
Trust me, whatever he's promised,he will go back on his word
相信我 不管他允諾了什麼 他都會食言的
And why should I trust a man who abandoned his own son
那我為什麼要相信你這個 拋棄自己兒子的人?
Because your brothers did
因為你的弟弟們相信了
They trusted a woman named Belle
他們相信了一個叫Belle的女人
They helped her get this box so we can defeat Pan
他們幫她拿到了這個盒子 好讓我們能打敗彼得潘
They're okay
他們沒事嗎?
For now, and only if we succeed
暫時沒事 而且只有我們成功才行
Wendy... we will save John and Michael,I swear to God
Wendy... 我們會救John和Michael的 我對天發誓
But right now,I really need your help.Please
但現在 我真的很需要你的幫助 拜託了
Pan told Henry that... he needs his heart to save magic
彼得潘告訴Henry... 他需要他的心來拯救魔法
But it's a lie
但那是個謊言
He needs it to save himself
他是需要那顆心來拯救自己
What do you mean
你是什麼意思?
Pan's dying
彼得潘要死了
He needs the heart of the truest believer to absorb all the magic in Neverland
他需要真正信徒的心來吸收 永恆島的全部魔力
And once he does... he will be immortal,all powerful
一旦他那麼做了... 他會長生不死 法力無邊
And what happens to Henry
那Henry會怎麼樣?
Well,it's a trade
這是個交易
When Pan lives, Henry will die
當彼得潘存活 Henry就會死
Ah,it's been a long time since I stepped foot on this shore
我好久沒有涉足這片海濱了
What's that
那是什麼?
It's a protection spell
是個保護咒
Now let's go.It's time
我們走吧 是時候了
How do we stop Pan
我們要怎麼阻止彼得潘?
Pan took Henry to Skull Rock
彼得潘帶著Henry去了骷髏洞穴
But you haven't got much time
但你們的時間不多了
Then we stay behind
那我們就留下
Someone needs to be here to guard the lost boys when they wake up
等迷失男孩們醒了 需要有人在這兒看守他們
- You don't need to stay behind - David's right
- 你不用留下 - David是對的
You get him home,tell him we love him
你帶他回家 告訴他我們愛他
Tell him yourself, when you get back from Deadman's Peak
你自己告訴他 等你們從亡靈峰回來
Gold can cure you back in Storybrooke
Gold能在童話鎮把你治癒
We just need to bring some of the water with us
我們只需要帶點水回去
And you... you didn't give up.Thank you
你... 你沒有放棄 謝謝你
Well,apparently,that's the only thanks I need these days
很明顯 這是我這些天僅需要的感謝了
Tink and I will take care of things here
我和叮噹仙女會負責好這邊
Meet you back at the "Jolly Roger" when you find Henry
等你找到Henry 我們在"海盜旗"下見
Promise me if your father and I don't make it back,you get him home
向我保證如果我和你父親沒能回來 你把他帶回家
We're all going back home.Together
我們都會回家的 一起回去
I'm tired
我走不動了
We're almost there
我們就快到了
We can rest all we want after we get the pixie dust,
等我們拿到精靈塵 想怎麼休息都成
do whatever your heart desires
想做什麼都成
Just wait.You'll see
再堅持會兒 你就會看到了
What does it look like
那是長什麼樣的
It's just like dust
看起來就像塵土一樣
You never know the power it contains just by looking at it
僅僅看著它 你永遠不會知道它所蘊含的能量
But when you believe in its power,
但當你相信了它的魔力
it glows with magic and becomes something very special indeed
它會隨著魔法增長 變成非常特別的東西
We're here
我們到了
All I see are trees
我只看見樹
That's because it's made in the flowers that grow on the highest of the branches
因為精靈塵蘊含於 生長在最高樹枝上的花朵裡
Where they're closest to the stars
那是它們最接近星星的地方
The flowers bloom at night,soak in the starlight
花兒在夜裡綻放 沐浴在星光之中
That's how the pixie dust gets its magic
這就是精靈塵獲得魔法的源泉
I haven't felt this excited in years,
我好幾年沒這麼興奮過了
since I was a boy about to climb one of those trees in my dreams
從我小時候就一直做夢 想爬這些樹
Come on,Rumple
來啊 Rumple
It'll be fun
會很有趣的
Hey... you wanna fly,you can't be afraid of heights
嘿... 你想飛翔 你就不能恐高
But I don't want to fly.You do
但我不想飛 是你想飛
But you will,son, once you see how it feels
但你會想飛的 孩子 一旦你見識過飛翔的感受
The wind whipping in your hair,the world below you
當風拂過你的發 世界都在你身下
Like you've not got a care in the world
好像這世界沒人在乎你似的
You're all alone.You're free
你孤身一人 你是自由的
Come on,I'll give you a boost
來吧 我給你墊一腳
But what if I fall
那要是我掉下來怎麼辦?
I promise you won't,hey
我向你保證你不會的 嘿
Don't make me,papa Please.I'm scared
不要逼我 爸爸 拜託了 我很害怕
I'm sorry,Rumple
對不起 Rumple
I just get excited
我只是太激動了
Why don't you wait here,and I'll go get the pixie dust for the both of us,hmm
要不你就在這兒等著 我去給我們倆拿精靈塵
- You promise not to be long - Aye
- 你保證不要太久了 - 好勒
I'll be as quick as a whip
我會快如閃電
Back before you know it
在你意識到以前就回來了
And then you'll see how wonderful Neverland can really be
然後你就會知道 永恆島到底有多麼神奇了
I want to fly
我想飛翔
Hello
有人嗎?
Is someone there
有人在嗎?
Who are you
你是誰?
I am the sole inhabitant of Neverland
我是永恆島的唯一居民
Then can you tell me what's wrong
那你能告訴我到底怎麼回事嗎?
Why can't I fly
我為什麼不能飛了?
You have to believe
你得相信
I'm trying,but it doesn't work
我很努力了 但就是沒用
Because you don't belong
因為你不屬於這兒
Papa.Papa.Papa
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸
These are Henry's shoes
這是Henry的鞋印
Wendy was right
Wendy說得沒錯
They're here
他們在這兒
Are you okay
你沒事吧?
I think so
沒事
What was that
那是什麼?
Pan cast a protection spell
彼得潘施了一個保護咒
There has to be a way to break it
肯定得有辦法能破了它
Careful with that
小心!
Try all you want,but Pan's magic is too powerful
隨你怎麼試 但彼得潘的魔法太強大了
At least for you
至少對你來說是這樣
Wha... How did you do that
什麼... 你是怎麼做到的?
The spell is designed to keep anyone who casts a shadow from entering
這個咒語是設計阻擋有影子的人的
And you don't have one
而你沒影子
You were telling the truth about ripping your shadow off
你說把你的影子割離了 那是真的
And Pan knows it
而彼得潘也知道這點
That's why he cast the spell he did
所以他才施了這麼個咒語
This isn't about keeping you out
目的不是把你們擋在外面
It's about drawing me in
而是為了把我引進去
He knows I won't give up the chance to finish what I came here to do
他知道我不會放過任何機會 來完成我此行的目的
You really did come here to save Henry
你真的是為了救Henry而來的
I gave you my trust with that box
我相信你 給了你那個盒子
Now I need you to give it back
現在我需要你把它還給我
You better come through,Gold
你最好成功回來 Gold
Or I'll make whatever Pan has planned for you look like child's play
不然我會讓彼得潘給你設的局 看起來像小孩子過家家
You understand me
聽明白沒有?
Well,a simple "good luck" would've sufficed
一句簡單的"祝你好運"就足夠了
So what are we supposed to do now
那我們現在該幹什麼?
What about the spell my father used to rip off his shadow
要不用我父親用來割裂影子的咒語呢?
You think if I knew how to do that, I wouldn't have done it already
你覺得要是我知道怎麼做 我不會已經那麼做了嗎?
- The moon
- 月亮 - 月亮?
The moon is what causes our shadows,right
是月亮讓我們有了影子 對吧?
What if there was a way to block it out using magic
要是用魔法能遮住月亮呢?
What,you mean like an eclipse
怎麼 你說像月蝕那樣?
Is that even possible
那可能嗎?
- Maybe - So
- 或許哦 - 所以說...
- I need help - With magic
- 我需要幫助 - 用魔法?
It requires a lot
需要大量魔法
I guess we're about to find out how much those lessons I gave you paid off
是時候檢驗我給你上的 那些魔法課是否有用了
Follow my lead
跟著我
This is it
就是這兒
The place where you're going to save magic
你將在這裡拯救魔法
Why does it have to be here
為什麼一定要在這兒?
Well,because this is the location from which Neverland's magic emanates
這是永恆島魔法起源之處
What's the hourglass for
這個沙漏是用來幹嘛的?
Marks how much time we have left before Neverland's magic runs out
它象徵著永恆島魔法剩餘的時間
It's almost empty
沙子快漏光了
- Is something wrong? - No.Come with me
- 有什麼問題嗎? - 不 跟我來吧
There's something I need to take care of before we get started,okay
在你開始前 我還有些事情要處理
What's wrong
怎麼了
- Rumple - Papa
- Rumple - 爸爸
I thought something terrible had happened to you
我以為你可能遇到危險了
No.No,I'm fine,son
不 不 我沒事 孩子
You don't have to worry about me
你不用擔心我
Did you get pixie dust
你找到精靈塵了嗎?
Yes
是的
But when I tried using it,it didn't work
我試了試它們 在我身上沒用
Why not
為什麼沒用
I'm not a boy anymore
因為我不再是個男孩了
You were right
你說的對
Neverland is just for children
永恆島只歡迎孩子
Adults don't belong here
成年人不屬於這兒
Then... we'll leave and go somewhere else
既然這樣 我們可以離開這兒 去其他地方
All that matters... is that we're together
只要我們在一起就好
I wish it was that easy
事情沒那麼簡單
But we both know wherever we go, I'll go back to my old ways
我們都明白 不論我們去哪兒 我還是會犯老毛病
I can never be the father you need me to be
我永遠都成不了你嚮往的那種父親
- I'm too weak - I don't understand
- 我太懦弱了 - 我不明白
What are you trying to say
你想說什麼?
That there is a way that I can stay here,
我想說我有辦法留在這兒
a way that I can get the pixie dust to work so I can fly again...
我有辦法讓精靈塵對我起作用
just like I was when I was a boy
就像當年我還是個男孩時的那樣
How
你要怎麼做?
By letting go of the thing that is holding me back... you
拋棄阻礙我的那個東西... 你
Help!A monster
救我! 有個怪物
It's not a monster,Rumple.It's a friend
它不是怪物 Rumple 它是朋友
It's part of the island
它是這個島的一部分
And after I do what it told me... I let you go... it will become part of me,too
我會照他說的做... 放你走 之後它也會變成我的一部分
Don't let him take me
別讓它帶走我
I don't have a choice
我無路可退
To stay here,I have to believe that I'm young again
要留在這兒 我要確信自己重返青春
And with you here to remind me,I can't
只要有你在這兒 我就做不到
No,papa,please.Help me
不 爸爸 求你了 救救我
A child can't have a child,Rumple
一個孩子是不會有兒子的 Rumple
I'm sorry but it's true
很抱歉 但這就是事實
Don't fight it
別和事實作對
We both know that you're better off without me
我們都知道 沒有我你會過得更好
I was never meant to be a father.No
- 我生來就不是當爹的料 - 不
Hello,laddie
你好 夥計
Oh,I see you've come bearing gifts
我看到你帶著禮物
Where's Henry
Henry在哪兒?
Oh,you mean my great-grandson
你說的可是我的曾孫?
You still haven't told the others who I really am
你還是沒告訴別人我的真實身份
Not even your own son
連你的兒子都沒說
Why
為什麼
Because you're nothing but a coward to me
因為對我來說 你只是個懦夫而已
We both know if that were true, I'd already be in that box
我們都明白 如果傳言是真的 我早就被關在那個盒子裡了
You don't think I can do it
你不相信我可以做到
- You let me inside just to,uh,taunt me. - No
- 你讓我進來就是為了嘲諷我嗎? - 不
To see you again, to give you one last chance
我想再見到你 再給你最後一次機會
Stay with me
和我待在一起吧
Let this go
放棄你的計劃
Let's start over
我們重新開始
Do you think I want to be with you
你認為我還想和你在一起嗎?
That I could ever forgive you after you abandoned me
當年你就這樣扔下我 你還指望我能原諒你?
I'm disappointed,Rumple
我很失望 Rumple
After all these years,I thought you'd be more...
那麼多年過去了 我以為你變得更...
understanding, considering you did the same thing to your son
理解我了 畢竟你也拋棄你的兒子
You traded Baelfire for the power of a dagger, and I traded you for youth
你用Baelfire交換了匕首的法力 我用你交換年輕
We're a lot more alike than you care to admit
我們其實很相似 儘管你不願承認
- We are nothing alike - Oh,of course we are
- 我們毫無相似之處 - 我們當然相似
And it's nothing to be ashamed of
沒什麼好羞於承認的
Neither one of us was cut out to be a father,m'boy
兒子 我們都不是當爹的料
I regretted leaving my son the moment I let him go
拋下我兒子的那一刻我就後悔了
I spent my life trying to find him, to get him back
我花了畢生精力找回他
And what did you do
而你呢?
You forgot about me
你把我徹底忘記了
I never forgot about you
我從沒忘記你
Why do you think I call myself "Peter Pan"
你以為我為什麼要 給自己取名"彼得潘"?
Don't think for a moment I believe it's because you care for me
別以為我會相信那是因為我
But I do
但事實如此
All you have to do is put down that box, and you'll see it's true
你只要放下盒子 就會知道 我說的都是真的
We can make the fresh start you always wanted, together, just as we planned
如你所願 我們一起重新開始 就像當年計劃的一樣
Oh,I'm gonna make a fresh start
我是要重新開始
Just not with you
但不是和你
I don't understand
我不明白
'Cause you don't have it
因為真正的潘多拉盒子在我這兒
- You switched them - Follow the lady
- 你掉包了 - 紙牌遊戲
Still having trouble believing
你還不相信
In Neverland,all you have to do is think of something to have it
在永恆島 只要你想著一樣東西 你就能擁有它
Even something fake
就算是個假的
But the real one... Well,let's see what it can do
而這個真的 讓我們看看它的威力
No.I'm sorry,Rumple
對不起 Rumple
You had your chance
你有過機會
The choice was yours
這是你自己的選擇
Come on
躺下
What happened to the bean
魔法豆在哪兒
He used it
他用掉了
He left me and he's never coming back
他拋下我 再也不會回來了
Oh,it's for the best,Rumple
Rumple 這樣對你來說最好
I'm alone now
我只剩一個人了
No,you have us... - And a wheel
- 不 你有我們 - 還有紡車輪
- You always have a home here
這裡永遠都是你的家
Now get some rest... And you'll feel better
現在好好休息 等到你感覺好一點了
Later we'll spin,hmm
之後我們會紡織
Where's your doll
你的玩偶呢?
I lost him
我掉了
Well,we'll make you another one
沒事 我們會為你再做一個
You can give it the same name
你可以給它取個同樣的名字
No.Peter Pan is gone forever
不 彼得潘再也回不來了
What is this place
這是哪兒?
I don't remember seeing it from my dreams
我在夢裡沒見過這兒
That's because it didn't exist
因為它並不存在
It was created when you made the decision to stay here
當你決定留下的時候 這裡才建成
A giant skull
巨大的骷髏
It's glorious
太棒了
What's the hourglass for
這個沙漏是用來幹嘛
It represents the magic fueling your youth,
它代表了維持你年輕的魔法
the magic allowing you to stay here, to stay young
讓你留下的魔法--保持年輕
And what happens when it runs out
沙子漏完了會發生什麼
Your youth will be taken and you will die
你的年輕會被奪走 你也會死去
But I thought I was going to stay young forever
但我以為我可以永遠年輕
Neverland is a place for children to visit in their dreams,
永恆島是孩子夢中的國度
not a place for them to live
並不是供他們生活的地方
You are the first to try to stay
你是第一個試圖留下的人
And in doing so,you're breaking the rules
你已經破壞了規矩
Any rule can be broken,especially here
任何規矩都可以被破壞 尤其在這兒
I made this place without even thinking about it
我想都沒想就建造了這個地方
- There has to be a way. - Perhaps
- 一定有辦法 - 也許吧
Then I will find it
我要找出這個辦法
I will find a way
我會找到辦法
I believe
我相信
It's time,Henry
是時候了 Henry
Time to save magic, to save Neverland
是時候拯救魔法 拯救永恆島了
What do I have to do
我該做些什麼
You must give me your heart,Henry... the heart of the truest believer
你需要給我你的心 Henry 最虔誠信徒的心
You mean... I have to believe
你的意思是... 我必須要相信
No,Henry
不 Henry
I mean,you need to give me your heart
我的意思是 你要給我你的心
But... what will happen to me
那我會怎麼樣
You'll become the greatest of all heroes
你會變成最偉大的英雄
You can tell me the truth
你可以說實話
I know all magic comes with a price
我知道所有魔法都有代價
Saving it must come with a price,too
拯救它們也會付出代價的
I would never lie to you,Henry
我不會騙你 Henry
I mean,you're right
你說得對
There is a price
的確有代價
You have to stay here on the island with me
你必須和我一起待在島上
Neverland will become your new home
永恆島是你的新家
I know it's a huge sacrifice,but isn't it worth it
我知道這是巨大的犧牲 但是難道不值得嗎?
Heroes have to make sacrifices all the time
英雄總要做出犧牲
My family taught me that
這是我家人教我的
Then they'd be proud if they could see you now, because you're about to save them all
如果他們現在能看到 一定會為你驕傲 因為你即將拯救所有人
- Now are you ready? - Yes
- 現在準備好了嗎? - 是的
Then let me help you
讓我幫你
Henry,wait
Henry 等等
Whatever Pan's telling you to do,don't do it
無論彼得潘讓你做什麼 都不要去做
- Dad.You're alive? - I am,buddy
- 爸爸 你還活著? - 是的 小傢伙
And I need you to listen to me
現在聽我說
Pan is lying to you
彼得潘在對你撒謊
Oh,pleasure to see you,too,Baelfire, not to mention the Savior and the Evil Queen
很高興看到你們 Baelfire 救世主和惡毒皇后
Henry, you need to get away from him now
Henry 遠離他
- He's trying to hurt you - No
- 他想要傷害你 - 不
The heart of the truest believer
最虔誠信徒的心臟
It's what's gonna save magic
它會拯救魔法
It's gonna save all of you
它會拯救所有人
No,it's not
不 不會
This was never about magic,Henry
Henry 這不關魔法的事
You have to believe us
你要相信我們
The only person Pan's interested in saving is himself
彼得潘只是在拯救他自己
That's not true
那不是真的
Of course it isn't
當然不是
Yes,it is
是的
Pan can't live without you dying
你不死 彼得潘也活不成
If you give him your heart,it's gonna kill you
如果你給了他你的心臟 你會死的
They're trying to stem your belief,Henry
Henry 他們想要動搖你的信念
But don't let them
別讓他們得逞
Remember,every hero gets tested
記住 每個英雄都會經受考驗
Henry... I know what being a hero looks like, and this isn't it
Henry... 我知道當一個英雄是 什麼樣的 絕對不是這樣的
Why would they lie
他們為什麼要撒謊?
Because that's what adults do,Henry
成年人就愛撒謊 Henry
You know that better than anyone
你比任何人知道得都更清楚
Henry... you have to believe us
Henry... 你要相信我們
Your parents don't care about Neverland,Henry
你的父母不在乎永恆島 Henry
They know if you give your heart to save it, then you'll have to stay
他們知道如果你用你的心臟 拯救這裡 你將會永遠待在這兒
They're being selfish because they don't wanna lose you
他們很自私 他們不想失去你
- Henry,you have to trust us - Trust!
- Henry 你要信任我們 - 信任!
I'm the only one who's ever been honest with you,Henry
我才是唯一對你誠實的人 Henry
The only one who ever believed in you
唯一相信你的人
This is your choice.Not theirs
這是你的選擇 不是他們的
You have to choose now
你現在必須選擇
We're running out of time
我們沒時間了
We believe in you,Henry.Because we love you
- 我們相信你 Henry - 因為我們愛你
More than anything
愛你勝過一切
I love you,too
我也愛你們
But I have to save magic
但我必須拯救魔法
No,no,no,no.I'm sorry
- 不 不 不 - 對不起
No.
不
Henry
Henry
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-Proudly Presents
-------------------------- 本論壇字幕僅翻譯交流學習之用 禁止任何商業用途否則後果自負 --------------------------
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com/bbs=-Sync: YTET-可可与可心
-=YTEY-伊甸園字幕組-歆組=- 翻譯: 梨渦淺笑 霄霄 怡豆 校對: 下周停播一集 時間軸: 可可與可心
Once Upon a Time 3 Episode 8
童話歸來 第三季 第8集